<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>data-science | Dr. D.</title>
    <link>/tag/data-science/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>data-science</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Robin Donatello, 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_huf04b1cfef9bd3535e59178ed913aa604_851_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>data-science</title>
      <link>/tag/data-science/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Center for Healthy Communities</title>
      <link>/project/chc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/chc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a member of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://datascience.csuchico.edu&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Data Science Initiative&lt;/a&gt;, I have been working with the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.csuchico.edu/chc/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Center for Healthy Communties&lt;/a&gt; since 2019 as a statistical consultant, data manager, providing data skills training workshops and managing Data Science student interns. I help the CHC streamline and organize their data processes, research and program evaluation tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary contract that I work on is the &lt;strong&gt;CalFresh Outreach Program&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CalFresh Food is a nutrition assistance program that helps low-income individuals and families buy the food they need. CalFresh Food dollars help stretch a tight food budget and help many people afford to incorporate healthy foods like fruits and vegetables into their diets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;data-product--deliverables&#34;&gt;Data Product / Deliverables&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://chc-cfo-reporting.csuchico.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Website for subcontractors to upload required reporting files quarterly.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Results of the Bsic needs Stucent Success Survey 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://chicocalfresh.github.io/bns-website/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;student-collaborators&#34;&gt;Student Collaborators&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brandon Leff [link to his author page]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning</title>
      <link>/project/cnn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/cnn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Paper surveys are still a preferred in-class data collection method due to the captive audience, ease of creation (e.g. MS word), and administration. Data entry is time consuming and expensive. This research explored using convolutional neural networks (CNN, a deep learning process) to automate the data entry of thousands of surveys administered as part of a college program assessment. CNN are used in image detection (e.g. is there a cute cat in the picture?), where digital images are stored as arrays with entries corresponding to pixel color. CNN’s are constructed by creating many layers that each apply specific matrix operations to extract the most salient characteristics in the image. Our work differs from image detection; our goal was to identify where a mark exists on a page (e.g. circles, x’s), and classify it as the corresponding response. Like other machine learning models, CNN depend on quality and quantity of training data, and can be computationally intensive but feasible on a moderate powered server. Preliminary results achieved 92% validation accuracy, demonstrating it’s feasible to use paper surveys without the burden of manual data entry or costly software licenses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;student-researcher&#34;&gt;Student Researcher&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;../../author/kristofer-walker/&#34;&gt;Kristofer Walker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;presentations&#34;&gt;Presentations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kris presented his work in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://jointmathematicsmeetings.org/meetings/national/jmm2020/2245_maasessstud#post&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Student Poster Session&lt;/a&gt; at the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://jointmathematicsmeetings.org/meetings/national/jmm2020/2245_intro&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;2020 Joint Math Meetings&lt;/a&gt;, January 15-18, 2020, Denver, CO.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>College of Natural Sciences Poster Session</title>
      <link>/project/nsc-poster/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/nsc-poster/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The annual College of Natural Sciences Poster Session is an established event where students, faculty and clubs have the opportunity to present their original research or student activities to the College, University and Chico Community. See more about the College Poser Session Event at the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.csuchico.edu/nsci/event/poster.shtml&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;College of Natural Sciences Poster Session event page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project streamlined the submitted abstract processing, and provided the authors with a website to view their submission. Another result from this project was the creation of a judging app that reduced the burden of vote tallying for multiple categories, provided real-time score graphs, and an instant display of winner titles and authors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract-submission-processing&#34;&gt;Abstract Submission processing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstracts are submitted using Google Forms. They are then processed using R (&lt;code&gt;googlesheets&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;stringr&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;dplyr&lt;/code&gt;), turned into a webpage using &lt;code&gt;rmarkdown&lt;/code&gt; with a few fancy visual aids using &lt;code&gt;ggplot2&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;kable&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The webpage is re-built nightly during the open abstract submission period and can be seen here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://norcalbiostat.github.io/CNS-Poster-Session/&#34;&gt;https://norcalbiostat.github.io/CNS-Poster-Session/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the abstract submission period closes, the poster ID&amp;rsquo;s are finalied and abstracts reviewed by members of the poster session committee. The &lt;code&gt;rmarkdown&lt;/code&gt; file gets compiled to PDF format and turned into a 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.csuchico.edu/nsci/_assets/documents/NSC-poster-session-2018-abstract-booklet.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;program booklet&lt;/a&gt; with only minimal manual processing of latex symbols.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;judging-shiny-app&#34;&gt;Judging Shiny App&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://norcalbiostat.shinyapps.io/CNSPosterJudgingApp/&#34;&gt;https://norcalbiostat.shinyapps.io/CNSPosterJudgingApp/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The app was originally created for the 2017 session by Aaron Shaffer 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ClassicSours&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;@ClassicSours&lt;/a&gt;, and updated by me for 2018. Feel free to play around, the data is not stored on app shutdown. The poster ID&amp;rsquo;s are listed on the abstract website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This judging app&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reduced the burden of vote tallying for multiple categories (judge votes, peoples choice)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;showed real-time vote scoring results as bar charts that could be viewed by anyone with the link (committee members only) during the session (an unexpected but amusing side-result)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;provided an instant display of winning poster titles with authors to be read off by the Dean during the awards ceremony (a mere 30 minutes after the voting period closes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;allowed for the download of merged voting data so
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;certificates could be made via mail merge by the next day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.csuchico.edu/gateway/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Gateway Scinece Museum&lt;/a&gt; has the contact information for authors for whom their posters have been chosen to be displayed in the Museum over summer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community Coding</title>
      <link>/project/community-coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/community-coding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;coding-is-a-social-activity&#34;&gt;Coding is a social activity!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never code alone :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Got data and working on analysis?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Got questions on using R or other programming languages?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Great way to dedicate time to working on that project you&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to get around to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come and hang out with other coders in a welcoming and supportive environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summer-2020-hours-wed-2-4pm-until-august-12&#34;&gt;Summer 2020 Hours: Wed 2-4pm until August 12&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please don&amp;rsquo;t forget to 
&lt;a href=&#34;bit.ly/community_coding&#34;&gt;sign in&lt;/a&gt;. This helps demonstrate that this service is used.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://csuchico.zoom.us/j/97998102303?pwd=Tkp0Mnhaek9HQUk0SGNOclEvaGZuUT09&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Zoom join link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;bit.ly/cc_hours&#34;&gt;Flyer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Want to contribute your time and expertise? Log in and let&amp;rsquo;s chat.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science Initative</title>
      <link>/project/dsi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/dsi/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataFest</title>
      <link>/project/data-fest/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/data-fest/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DS POLS Twitter project</title>
      <link>/project/ds-pols/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/ds-pols/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project</title>
      <link>/project/blank/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/blank/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
