<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Statistics | Dr. D.</title>
    <link>/tag/statistics/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/statistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Statistics</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Robin Donatello, 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_huf04b1cfef9bd3535e59178ed913aa604_851_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Statistics</title>
      <link>/tag/statistics/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adolescent and School Health</title>
      <link>/project/ash/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/ash/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been working with the ASH unit since 2007. Here is a summary of the projects this research group has worked on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-connect-2005-2010&#34;&gt;Project Connect (2005-2010)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Project Connect was a teenage pregnancy and STD prevention study conducted in LAUSD schools. Twelve high schools in areas with STD and pregnancy rates exceeding the Healthy People 2010 [14] goals were matched into six pairs based on criteria including chlamydia and birth rates, school demographics, and number of students, and were invited to participate. To minimize contamination between conditions, the schools in each pair were purposively assigned to either the intervention or control condition so that no intervention school attendance area shared a geographic boundary with any control school. Schools were matched using publicly available data before any staff contact with school personnel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;keeping-it-real-lac-2010--2015&#34;&gt;Keeping It Real LAC (2010 -2015)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Funded through the Office of Adolescent Health, Keeping It Real LAC (KIR) trained 7th and 8th grade teachers in 24 CUSD and LAUSD middle schools in the evidence-based, abstinence-plus curriculum It’s Your Game…Keep It Real! (IYG). KIR demonstrated that, with appropriate training and support, middle school teachers are capable of delivering evidence-based sexual health education that impacts student risk behaviors. The success of KIR and the growing demand for the IYG curriculum provided powerful evidence of its fit in Los Angeles, and paved the way for KIR-T.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;keeping-it-real-together-2015-2020&#34;&gt;Keeping It Real Together (2015-2020)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeping It Real Together (KIR-T) is a multi-agency collaborative that works to to reduce and prevent teen pregnancy and sexually transmitted diseases among Los Angeles County youth. Our goal is to change the landscape of sexual health in Los Angeles County through school-based sexual health education, parent workshops, improved access to health services, and community mobilization and partnership&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more details on program outcomes and success stories see &lt;a href=&#34;https://keepingitrealtogether.org/&#34;&gt;https://keepingitrealtogether.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;related-publications--presentations&#34;&gt;Related Publications &amp;amp; Presentations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jadohealth.2018.09.021&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Effectiveness Evaluation of It’s Your Game; Keep It Real, a Middle School HIV/Sexually Transmitted Infection/Pregnancy Prevention Program (2018)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jadohealth.2017.07.017&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Structural Intervention With School Nurses Increases Receipt of Sexual Health Care Among Male High School Students (2017)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dx.doi.org/10.1080/00224499.2016.1164800&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Patterns of Sexual Experience Among Urban Latino and African American Ninth Grade Students (2016)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jadohealth.2012.03.010&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Improving the Implementation of a Condom Availability Program in Urban High Schools (2012)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jadohealth.2014.04.005&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Project Connect Health Systems Intervention: Linking Sexually
Experienced Youth to Sexual and Reproductive Health Care (2014)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Institutional Learning through Empirical Assessment and Researching iNterventions</title>
      <link>/project/ilearn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/ilearn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The iLEARN project will initiate a systematic, institutional approach to assessing the impact of programs on student success. The preliminary assessment will concentrate on interventions currently in practice at the university. In particular, we will investigate the following active programs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spring 2019 Course Redesign Faculty Learning Community (FLC)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Academic Probation workshops&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supplemental Instruction programs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of iLEARN is to close the loop on interventions by rigorously analyzing the effectiveness of current programs intended to improve student success (establish a baseline, make changes, re-evaluate program, increment additional changes or cancel intervention.)  In addition, the iLEARN project will also incorporate existing surveys (i.e, BCSSE, NSSE, FSSE) to provide supplemental insights for predicting student success and enabling the university to place students in early intervention programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We began sharing project activity ideas in March 2019. Project analysis work will start in Summer 2020 and extend into the 20-21AY&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;partners&#34;&gt;Partners&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.csuchico.edu/csci/people/faculty/buffardi-kevin.shtml&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Kevin Buffardi&lt;/a&gt; (Computer Science)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ian Donatello (
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.csuchico.edu/ir/index.shtml&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Institutional Research&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Passion Driven Statistics - Statistics to support science</title>
      <link>/project/chem-ss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/chem-ss/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PMA6</title>
      <link>/project/pma6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/pma6/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Multivariate Statistics 6th ed.</title>
      <link>/publication/pma6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/pma6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the sixth edition of a popular textbook on multivariate analysis. Well-regarded for its practical and accessible approach, with excellent examples and good guidance on computing, the book is particularly popular for teaching outside statistics, i.e. in epidemiology, social science, business, etc. The sixth edition has been updated with a new chapter on data visualization, a distinction made between exploratory and confirmatory analyses and a new section on generalized estimating equations and many new updates throughout. This new edition will enable the book to continue as one of the leading textbooks in the area, particularly for non-statisticians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;book_cover.png&#34; alt=&#34;book cover&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community Coding</title>
      <link>/project/community-coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/community-coding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;coding-is-a-social-activity&#34;&gt;Coding is a social activity!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never code alone :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Got data and working on analysis?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Got questions on using R or other programming languages?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Great way to dedicate time to working on that project you&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to get around to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come and hang out with other coders in a welcoming and supportive environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summer-2020-hours-wed-2-4pm-until-august-12&#34;&gt;Summer 2020 Hours: Wed 2-4pm until August 12&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please don&amp;rsquo;t forget to 
&lt;a href=&#34;bit.ly/community_coding&#34;&gt;sign in&lt;/a&gt;. This helps demonstrate that this service is used.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://csuchico.zoom.us/j/97998102303?pwd=Tkp0Mnhaek9HQUk0SGNOclEvaGZuUT09&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Zoom join link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;bit.ly/cc_hours&#34;&gt;Flyer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Want to contribute your time and expertise? Log in and let&amp;rsquo;s chat.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataFest</title>
      <link>/project/data-fest/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/data-fest/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Missing Data</title>
      <link>/project/missing-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/missing-data/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
